Finding Aid for Learning Disabilities Association of Michigan Records, 1965-2003
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Affiliated Organizations and Activities
  The Affiliated Organizations and Activities series is organized into four sub-series: CAUSE, SEAC, Grants and Projects, and Publications. The CAUSE sub-series contains materials which document some of the activities, policies, and structure of this organization such as board of directors meetings, by-laws, organizational directories, financial statements, manuals, workshops and various projects in which CAUSE participated. The SEAC sub-series consists of mostly meeting materials produced by the committee in its advisory capacity to Michigan's Department of Education between 1993-2000. The Grants and Projects sub-series contains materials from three grants in which the LDAM played a role in developing and implementing: The Comprehensive Parent Service Systems grant (CPSS), the Northwest Michigan Community Partner Transition Initiative grant (NMCPTI), and the Parent Coalition grant. This sub-series also contains materials from the Growth for Families Conference held in 1999. Finally, the Publications sub-series contains various publications and reports concerning learning disabilities and special education.
  - CAUSE
    - Board of Directors Meetings 2000-2002 (Box 3)
    - By-Laws 2001 (Box 3)
    - Directories 2000-2001 (Box 3)
    - Executive Director Issues 2002 (Box 3)
    - Financial Statements 2001-2002 (Box 3)
    - Job Descriptions (Box 3)
    - Legislation 2001-2002 (Box 3)
    - Personnel Policies Procedures Manual 2001 (Box 3)
    - Projects 1997-2001 (Box 3)
    - Student and Family Support Grant 1994 (Box 3)
    - Workshops 2002 (Box 3)
    - Rulings Manual 1994, 4 folders (Box 3)
    - Rulings Manual Update, issues 1-3 1995 (Box 3)
  - SEAC
    - Meeting Materials 1993-1997, 12 folders (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous 1995-2000 (Box 4)
  - Grants and Projects
    - CPSS 1998
      - Part I: "RFP" (Box 4)
      - Part II: "Resumes" (Box 4)
      - Part III: "Commitment" (Box 4)
      - Part IV: "Support" (Box 4)
      - Part V: "Budget" (Box 4)
      - Part VI: "Organization" (Box 4)
      - Part VII: "Training" (Box 4)
      - Part VIII: "Coordination" (Box 4)
      - Part IX: "Evaluation" (Box 4)
      - Part X: "Budget" (Box 4)
      - Part XI (Box 4)
    - NMCPTI 1994
      - Part I (Box 4)
      - Part II (Box 4)
      - Part III (Box 4)
      - Part IV (Box 4)
      - Part V: "Reporting Requirements" (Box 4)
      - Part VI: "Calendar" (Box 4)
      - Part VII: "Initiative Organization (Overview)" (Box 4)
      - Part VIII: "S & F Support Network" (Box 4)
      - Part IX: "University Regional Supports" (Box 4)
      - Part X: "Initiative Networking and Dissemination" (Box 4)
      - Part XI (Box 4)
    - Parent Coalition Grant 1999 (Box 4)
    - Growth for Families Conference, parts I-IV 1999 (Box 4)
  - Publications
    - "Michigan's Strategic Plan for Students With Visual Impairment" (Draft) (Box 4)
    - AUENSD
      - "Supported Independence" (Box 4)
      - "Functional Independence" (Box 4)
      - "Participation" (Box 4)
    - "Special Education Program Outcomes Guide: Learning Disabilities," 1992 (Box 4)
    - "Special Education Program Outcomes Supplement: Outcome Assessment Strategy: Learning Disabilities," 1992 (Box 4)
    - "Special Education Into the 21st Century," 1993, 2 folders (Box 4)